{"tossups": [{"question": "President and position required. The first holder of this position under this president earned a nickname during the selection process for the state flower of Texas. The second holder of this position also served as Secretary of Agriculture under this same president. The third holder of this position held it for less than a year after being nominated to it in an event called the \u201cSecond Missouri Compromise.\u201d For ten points, what is this position that John Garner, Henry Wallace, and Harry Truman held under this president?", "answer": "<em><b> V</b></em> ice<em><b> P</b></em>resident of<em><b> F</b></em>ranklin Delano<em><b> Roosevelt</b></em> (accept<em><b> FDR</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One of these places in Minsk, called \u201cThe Pit,\u201d shows a group of people descending a staircase. Another one of these places in Germany has a constantly looping video of two men kissing. The newest of these installations in the Tiergarten has a memorial pool in the shape of a wheel, with a triangle in the center, and honors the Romani people. For ten points, name these commemorative public art institutions, the largest of which is Berlin\u2019s Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe.", "answer": "<em><b> Holocaust Memorials</b></em> (accept equivalents for<em><b> memorial</b></em>, such as<em><b> monument</b></em> or<em><b> statues</b></em>; prompt on more general answers that don\u2019t mention the<em><b> Holocaust</b></em>, like \u201cWorld War II Memorials\u201d)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "While in Sweden, this person learned Swedish to work with Anders Bruzelius on civil procedure. In Frontiero v. Richardson, this person argued that Air Force Lieutenant Sharron Frontiero could claim her husband as a \u201cdependent.\u201d Replacing Byron White in 1993, this person authored an opinion on gender discrimination at the Virginia Military Institute. For ten points, name this woman who died in September, 2020, the second female Supreme Court justice.", "answer": "Ruth Bader<em><b> Ginsburg</b></em> (accept<em><b> R.B.G.</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man refused to visit victims of the Great Mississippi Flood due to his belief that it would be political grandstanding. Democrat John W. Davis and Progressive Robert LaFollette both lost an election to this man. This man responded to a Samuel Gompers telegram by claiming that \u201cthere is no right to strike against public safety,\u201d gaining national attention for his suppression of the Boston Police Strike. For ten points, name this \u201csilent\u201d president who succeeded Warren Harding.", "answer": "Calvin<em><b> Coolidge</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A novel about a folk hero from this country has a style that parallels that title character\u2019s Jerilderie Letter. Another novel by an author from this country focuses on a man who received the title \u201cRighteous Among Nations\u201d at the Yad Vashem Memorial for his efforts in convincing German authorities that he needed to hire Jews during World War Two. For ten points, name this home country of the author of Schindler\u2019s Ark, Thomas Keneally, and of the bushranger Ned Kelly.", "answer": "Commonwealth of<em><b> Australia</b></em> Page 1", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "At a World War One battle off the coast of this country, the SMS Emden quickly sank the Zhemchug and Mousquet. A region in this country includes an island once named for the Prince of Wales and a capital city named for George III, George Town. The Battle of Penang took place in what is now this country in the Strait of Malacca. Tunku Abdul Rahman was the first Prime Minister of, for ten points, what Asian country that expelled Singapore in 1965?", "answer": "<em><b> Malaysia</b></em>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Three days after this event, a ceremony was held that is depicted in the painting The Distribution of the Eagle Standards. Pope Pius VII was present at this event, three years after signing a Concordat with this event\u2019s central figure. This event took place at Notre Dame Cathedral instead of the traditional Reims [RONCE], and a David [dah-VEED] painting of this event depicts a kneeling Josephine. For ten points, name this December 2, 1804 event in which a Frenchman crowned himself emperor.", "answer": "<em><b> Coronation</b></em> of<em><b> Napoleon</b></em> (accept descriptions of<em><b> Napoleon</b></em> becoming<em><b> emperor</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The first Naval Reserve Officer Training Corps was established at this university by Chester Nimitz. A memorial for James Rector was held in this university\u2019s Sproul Plaza after a violent protest at its People\u2019s Park. The Symbionese Liberation Army kidnapped Patty Hearst while she studied at this university. This university is named for an idealist Anglo-Irish philosopher and is known for its activism during the Free Speech Movement. For ten points, name this public California university.", "answer": "U(niversity) of C(alifornia),<em><b> Berkeley</b></em> (prompt on \u201cCal\u201d or \u201cCalifornia\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This artist wrote and recorded the song \u201cHappy Birthday\u201d to advocate for Martin Luther King, Jr. Day becoming a federal holiday. This musician\u2019s \u201cclassic period\u201d was from 1972 to 1977, when he released the albums Talking Book and Songs in the Key of Life. This man acknowledged influential Black musicians in the song \u201cSir Duke\u201d and became the youngest ever to top the charts at age 13 in 1963. For ten points, name this influential R&B musician who wrote \u201cFor Once in My Life\u201d and \u201cSuperstition.\u201d", "answer": "Stevie<em><b> Wonder</b></em> (accept Stevland Hardaway<em><b> Morris</b></em> or Stevland Hardaway<em><b> Judkins</b></em>)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This man placed a likeness of his own head onto the Colossus of Nero and declared that he was the\u201conly left handed fighter to conquer twelve times one thousand men.\u201d Twenty-five consuls were appointed in a single year after this man\u2019s advisor Cleander sold public offices. This man was strangled by the wrestler Narcissus after the Plebeian games, where he had slain hundreds of beasts in an attempt to identify as Hercules. For ten points, identify this emperor, the son of Marcus Aurelius.", "answer": "<em><b> Commodus</b></em> Page 2", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This city\u2019s biggest library has an angular glass ceiling covered in diamond girders designed by Rem Koolhaas. This city\u2019s neighborhood of Northgate contains one of the first malls and is the site of an NHL franchise planned for 2021. This city\u2019s best known structure was built for the 1962 World\u2019s Fair and can withstand forces as strong as the nearby 1700 Cascadia earthquake. For ten points, name this city, the birthplace of Jay Inslee and Bill Gates and the site of the Space Needle.", "answer": "<em><b> Seattle</b></em>, Washington", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "This man and Robert Norris were disgraced after a failed expedition to Lisbon to support a Portuguese rebellion against Philip II. This man legendarily stated that he had plenty of time to finish a game of bowls at Plymouth Hoe before tackling an enemy fleet. This man was described as having \u201csinged the king of Spain\u2019s beard\u201d in his attack on Cadiz that delayed the Spanish Armada. For ten points, name this English sea captain who circumnavigated the globe aboard the Golden Hind.", "answer": "Sir Francis<em><b> Drake</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "In a book titled for this man\u2019s \u201cBlack Box,\u201d Michael Behe coined the term \u201cirreducible complexity\u201dto argue against this man\u2019s theories. This man\u2019s theories are presented as \u201ccranes\u201d in a book by Daniel Dennet titled for this man\u2019s \u201cDangerous Idea.\u201d This man argued for the common ancestry of animals and humans in Descent of Man. For ten points, name this man who outlined the theory of natural selection in On the Origin of Species.", "answer": "Charles<em><b> Darwin</b></em>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "Members of this ethnic group gathered at Bastion Point for a 1977 protest. A 1960s protest movement of these people arose after their land rights were restricted by their namesake Affairs Amendment Act, which was seen as a treacherous act of the Pakeha [PAH-kih-hah]. These people lost much of their land during the invasion of Waikato. These people signed the Treaty of Waitangi with the British on North Island. For ten points, name these indigenous Polynesian people of New Zealand.", "answer": "<em><b> Maori</b></em>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This megacity, more accurately referred to as an \u201curban agglomeration,\u201d became the capital of its colony in 1914 and continued as capital after its nation\u2019s independence in 1960 until the capital moved in 1991. This city, south of Ibadan, is projected to double in size by 2050 to more than 16 million people. Movies like The Wedding Party were produced by this city\u2019s \u201cNollywood\u201d industry. For ten points, name this city with the largest metropolitan population in Africa, located in Nigeria.", "answer": "<em><b> Lagos</b></em>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "Isaac Babel and Osip Mandelstam were among the writers targeted in this event, the latter of whom was sent to a labor camp after reciting an \u201cEpigram\u201d against its overseer. Special troikas carried out extrajudicial punishments during this period and were led by the NKVD. During this period Lev Kamenev and Grigory Zinoviev were among the men convicted during a series of show trials in Moscow. Lasting from 1936 to 1938, name this major crackdown on opposition under Stalin.", "answer": "<em><b> Great Purge</b></em> (accept<em><b> Great Terror</b></em>,<em><b> Year of \u201837</b></em>, or<em><b> Yezhovschina</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man reestablished the Independent Treasury System and reduced the rates set by the Black Tariff by signing the Walker Tariff. This man had the shortest presidential retirement, surviving only three months after leaving office, and was the only president who was previously Speaker of the House. The rallying cry \u201c54-40 or fight\u201d was used by supporters of this man in reference to the annexation of Oregon. For ten points, name this president who presided over the Mexican-American War.", "answer": "James Knox<em><b> Polk</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Following the Holocaust, these institutions became refuges for Jewish intellectuals such as Ernst Borinski, who began working at one of these institutions in Tougaloo, Mississippi. After losing his right arm at the Battle of (+) Seven Pines, a Union general known as the\u201cChristian general\u201d founded one of these institutions in Washington, D.C. A number of these institutions were funded by the Second Morrill Act, including one in (*) </b> Alabama where the Tuskegee Airmen trained and attended classes. For ten points, name these institutions which include Morehouse College and Howard University.", "answer": "<em><b> Historically</b></em> <em><b>Black</b></em> <em><b>Colleges</b></em> <em><b>and</b></em> <em><b>Universities</b></em> (accept<em><b> HBCU</b></em> s, accept answers containing both or either of<em><b> Colleges</b></em> or<em><b> Universities</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This man created earldoms for his brothers, Gyrth and Leofwine, and was on good terms with Stigand, the archbishop of Canterbury. After this man was captured by Guy of Ponthieu, he joined his chief rival on a campaign in Brittany. (+) Tostig, this man\u2019s brother, won at Gate Fulford with the help of a rival of this man with the epithet \u201cHardrada.\u201d This man\u2019s sister Edith married Edward the Confessor, and this man was (*)</b> crowned the day after Edward\u2019s death. For ten points, who is this king of England who after winning at Stamford Bridge was defeated at the Battle of Hastings by William of Normandy?", "answer": "<em><b> Harold Godwinson</b></em> (accept<em><b> Harold II</b></em> )", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This person\u2019s great uncle was Lebanese-American historian Philip Hitti, who pioneered Arabic studies in the U.S. Barbara Morgan served as backup for this person, who was to present two 15 minute (+) classes, including \u201cWhere We\u2019ve Been, Where We\u2019re Going, Why\u201d and \u201cThe Ultimate Field Trip.\u201d Nebraska honors this educator with a namesake award for courage. Part of a team including Francis (*)</b> Scobee and Judith Resnick, this woman died after rubber O-rings failed, leading to a catastrophic explosion. For ten points, name this astronaut and teacher who died in the Challenger disaster.", "answer": "Christa<em><b> McAuliffe</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This leader gave a speech in which he encouraged revolution by instructing civilians to \u201cturn every house into a fort.\u201d The death of Zahurul Haq led to this leader\u2019s acquittal in the Agartala Conspiracy. This leader commanded the Rakkhi Bahini private militias to enforce a one-party state under his (+) Awami League. Operation Searchlight targeted this man\u2019s country, which underwent a major famine in 1974. This man is popularly known as (*)</b> \u201cBangabandhu,\u201d and his daughter became Prime Minister of their nation thirty-seven years after this man left office. For ten points, name this first post-independence president of Bangladesh.", "answer": "Sheikh Mujibur<em><b> Rahman</b></em> (accept Sheikh<em><b> Mujib</b></em>) Page 9", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>During this period, the Jisha-Bungyo, the highest ranking of the three administrators, was tasked with overseeing temples. The Okamoto Daihachi incident caused a leader in this period to ban (+) Christianity. Thousands of foreign traders were executed during this period in the aftermath of the Shimabara Rebellion. A work by Jason Josephson-Storm posits that Japan had no concept of religion until after the Black Ships of (*) </b> Admiral Matthew Perry appeared, forcing the government to open its ports during this period. For ten points, name this feudal military government, the last shogunate of Japan.", "answer": "<em><b> Tokugawa</b></em> Shogunate (accept \u201cPeriod\u201d in place of \u201cShogunate,\u201d accept<em><b> Edo</b></em> Shogunate)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>Abraham Mendel Theben used his influence with this ruler to exonerate Jews accused of blood libel. This monarch appointed Gerard von Swieten to investigate the supposed spread of vampires in her kingdom. This monarch\u2019s advisor, the Prince of (+) Kaunitz, engineered the switching of alliances in the Diplomatic Revolution. Frederick the Great invaded this ruler\u2019s territory of (*) </b> Silesia, sparking the War of Austrian Succession. For ten points, name this Austrian empress guaranteed the throne by her father\u2019s Pragmatic Sanction.", "answer": "<em><b> Maria Theresa</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>Water was originally trapped in this lake by mudflows caused by the eruption of Mount Pluto. The region around this lake was inhabited by the Washoe, and Cave Rock on this lake\u2019s shore is considered sacred. This lake has had many names, including Lake (+) Bigler and Fremont\u2019s Lake, after the first Euro-American to see it. Ski areas on this lake include Heavenly Mountain Resort and (*) </b> Squaw Valley, the site of the 1960 Winter Olympics. For ten points, name this largest alpine lake in North America, located on the California-Nevada border.", "answer": "Lake<em><b> Tahoe</b></em>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b>A Union general with this surname was promoted to major general after Gettysburg for his defense of Little Round Top and had the first name Gouvernor. Jonathan Trumbull depicted the death of a man with this surname at Breed\u2019s Hill. (+) Joseph was an American commander at Bunker Hill with this surname, which also belongs to a man who served three terms as governor of California before taking over Fred (*)</b> Vinson\u2019s seat on the Supreme Court. That man also wrote the majority opinions in Loving v. Virginia and Miranda v. Arizona. For ten points, what surname do these people share?", "answer": "<em><b> Warren</b></em> Page 10", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>A Nazi labor camp was built in this German state\u2019s Osterstein Castle. In the early twentieth century, the Horch automotive company was founded in this state which later was the site of the founding of Audi. Carl Wolff invented a safety lamp that helped grow the booming (+) coal mining industry in this state\u2019s city of Zwickau. Arthur Harris originally proposed an attack on Chemnitz and two other cities in this state. That plan ended up causing (*)</b> \u201cutter destruction\u201d in just one of its cities in an event detailed in Slaughterhouse-Five. For ten points, name this German state which saw the bombing of Dresden.", "answer": "Free State of<em><b> Saxony</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}